Leo Sammarco

Senior Frontend Engineer

PHONE EMAIL WEBSITE ADDRESS +447854882550 leosammarco@hotmail.com https://mediamonkfish.com

42 Manchester Grove Isle of Dogs, E14 3BG

OVERVIEW

Confident, motivated and passionate frontend engineer with over 8 years of industry experience. A keen interest in best practices, ways of working and observability. Focused on building, testing and deploying the right product whilst sharing learnings through quality documentation and mentoring.

Working with technologies including React, Node.js, Express, React Testing Library, Jest, server-side rendering (SSR), Typescript, AWS, GoCD.

EXPERIENCE

Booking.com Transport - Senior Software Engineer, May 2017 – Present

- Owner and maintainer of public facing website using React (functional components, hooks, context), Node.js, Express, SSR, Webpack.
- Building responsive on-brand components to work in a variety of browsers and supporting over 40 languages across the world.
- Developed internal tooling adopted by the company's engineering strategy.
- Actively contributing and staying up to date with the in-house tech radar.
- Built monitoring dashboards and set up alerting to watch for the 4 golden signals.
- Engrained agile ways of working in team to reflect and improve on various metrics such as cycle time and variance.
- Mentored graduates and new team members to help familiarise them with business processes, pairing and setting personal objectives.
- Regularly conducting interviews for senior software engineers.

Studio Skylab - Web Developer, May 2016 - May 2017

- Delivered website for Red Bull Advanced Technologies.
- Working in a small agency, collaborating with various clients to understand their needs and deliver features within budget.
- Developed in house tooling using Angular 4 as an opportunity to learn.
- Supporting and contributing to an in house WordPress design system made up of reusable components for use with every client.

UKFast - Web Developer, February 2016 - May 2016

- Maintaining custom hosting and billing portal using PHP.
- Built TechMCR portfolio website using AngularJS, Gulp, Sass.
- Focused on pixel perfect design and smooth animations using CSS3.
- Prioritising deliverables based on dependencies such as copy and design content.

Bright Future Software - Software Developer, September 2012 - February 2016

- Started off as an apprentice software developer gaining real world experience from the start.
- Shortlisted for national apprentice of the year.
- Developing applications for clients such as Cisco using AngularJS.
- Progressing to software developer within a year, took on more responsibilities such as leading a team of apprentice developers, engraining agile culture whilst liaising with product owners to deliver features on time.

QUALIFICATIONS

- MongoDB for Node.js Developers M101JS Certification
- Microsoft 70-480 Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

EDUCATION

- BTEC Level 4 HNC Diploma in Computing and Systems Development 2014
- BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma in Software Development 2013
- 12 A* C GCSEs at Altrincham Grammar School for Boys